Contact

kiddphunk@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kiddphunk (LinkedIn) beatspixelscodelife.com/about/ (Other) kiddphunk.com (Other)

Top Skills

Figma (Software)
Python (Programming Language)
yWorks

Ian Timourian

Data Visualizer, Creative Technologist, UI/UX Developer, Lead Interface Developer, Hacker, Digital Artist.

Great Cacapon, West Virginia, United States

Summary

My mission: to create interfaces and experiences that aim to unify, inspire and harness our collective spirits and shared knowledge.

I design and develop clean, commented architectures and interfaces utilizing: JavaScript, CoffeeScript, D3, React, Figma, jQuery, Processing, HTML/CSS, Web2.0 APIs, Adobe tools.

Specialties:

- * 20+ years design and programming experience
- * Background in distributed systems architecture
- * User interface (UI) design, architecture and prototyping
- * Visualizations of complex data sets
- * Information architecture and design
- * Design language development
- * Requirements gathering, analysis and distillation
- * Music production, remixing, DJing
- * Computer-generated art

Experience

DataRobot
Principal UX Designer
January 2020 - August 2022 (2 years 8 months)
San Francisco Bay Area

• Created Figma designs for DataPrep and Machine Learning applications.

Page 1 of 5

• Worked with Design and Product teams to brainstorm features and solutions.

Selected R&D coding/design projects:

- 3D visualization of the data flowing through the DataRobot system.
- Designed graph (DAG) framework ('graphkit').
- Utilized graphkit and Python to visualize DAG structure of Jupyter notebook cells.

[Figma, JavaScript, CoffeeScript, yWorks, three.js, Python, React]

Paxata

Lead UI/UX Engineer, Designer and Data Visualizer October 2012 - January 2020 (7 years 4 months)

Redwood City, California, United States

- Responsible for the look-and-feel of the Paxata application.
- Designed and coded the UI for the popular Filtergrams™ (filtering histograms) and the visualization-infused data grid, as well as other aspects of the system.
- Developed patterns that became industry-standard concepts across dataprep offerings from subsequent vendors.
- Researched and prototyped myriad features that were ultimately not integrated (data quality, etc).

Paxata is the industry's first self-service Adaptive Data Preparation™ platform that lets business analysts rapidly connect, explore, transform and combine data with the same freedom they are used to in their analytic discovery.

(Paxata was acquired by DataRobot in 2020.)

[D3, CoffeeScript, JavaScript, AngularJS]

Tidemark Systems, Inc. Lead UI/UX Architect April 2010 - April 2011 (1 year 1 month)

Researched and developed UI and visualization techniques for advancing the state-of-the-art in BI (Business Intelligence), and business software in general. Developed the look-and-feel of the Proferi web application, developed the initial prototypes and client UI framework, created a generic visualization

architecture, and co-developed a set of general patterns / Information Architecture to be reused as the platform continues to expand.

[JavaScript, CoffeeScript, SproutCore]

Sprout

Flex/Flash/R&D Developer September 2007 - December 2008 (1 year 4 months)

R&D Developer on one of the most advanced Flex applications to date. Created modular components for the Sprout system, investigated and implemented 3rd-party services into the Sprout framework, and prototyped new and novel enhancements to the core platform.

[Flex, ActionScript, Flash, UI, architecture, 'web-2.0' APIs]

Groovr

Django and Flash Hacker May 2007 - August 2007 (4 months)

Assisted Groovr in developing the site.

[Flash, Django, Python, HTML/CSS, UI]

RIVR Media / needled.com Flex and Django Architect January 2007 - June 2007 (6 months)

Developed and implemented an advanced site architecture and interactive design using 'Flango', a self-coined and powerful pairing of both Flex/ ActionScript and Django/Python technologies.

[Python, Django, Flex, ActionScript, HTML/CSS, UI, architecture]

GE Healthcare

Lead Interface Developer December 2005 - May 2006 (6 months)

The Davinci Project (contract/skunk-works). Sole technical developer of a Flex-based, next-generation clinical application prototype. Part of a select team of 4 chosen to develop a vision for clinical workflow management, true multi-modal interactivity, clinical collaboration, and workspace organization. Handled technical development of the UI and contributed highly with interactivity decisions.

[Flex, ActionScript, UI, architecture, healthcare]

futuretrax.net
Interface Developer/Consultant
January 2004 - August 2004 (8 months)

Implemented an advanced music player to listen to music on the futuretrax network. Created a music and metadata content management system.

[Flash, ActionScript, PHP, UI, music streaming]

Akamai Technologies Systems Engineer March 2001 - October 2002 (1 year 8 months)

Designed and implemented a perl/HTML architecture for dynamic and collaborative workflows, improving the efficiency of server deployments and monitoring.

[perl, HTML/CSS, UI, architecture]

Iconomy, Inc.
Software Developer
January 1999 - October 2000 (1 year 10 months)

Led technical development of a Java servlet-based web infrastructure designed to maximize UI-object reuse across multiple websites and a to provide a clean separation between style, data and design layers.

[Java, servlets, HTML, UI, architecture, dot-bomb survival techniques]

Trusted Information Systems Software Developer 1995 - 1998 (3 years)

Worked with various research and development groups on NSA- and DARPAfunded computer security projects.

[C++, DNS, secret keeping]

Education

Carnegie Mellon University

MSIN, Information Networking · (1997 - 1998)

Duke University
BSE, Electrical Engineering · (1993 - 1997)

Duke University
BS, Computer Science · (1993 - 1997)

Glenelg High School